[{"id": "591c37a4815febcc896f9272", "question": "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosphorus Strait?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b36fc51c3f17ccc40c8e10", "question": "What does Anna Crowe say out loud in the Italian restaurant shortly after Malcolm Crowe arrives?", "answer": "Happy Anniversary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0d29469bb8041d07a059", "question": "Earl Grey tea is blended with oil extracted from what fruit?", "answer": "Bergamot Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb4", "question": "What violinist performed the title character's solos in the film \"Fiddler on the Roof\"?", "answer": "Isaac Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ed6206d333868d34d76c", "question": "Which famous European structure was only supposed to stand for twenty years when it was built?", "answer": "Eiffel Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a021", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", which member of the Griffin family is Herbert infatuated with?", "answer": "Chris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ee", "question": "Gastroenteritis is the inflammation of what?", "answer": "Stomach and intestines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007810cbd51d85e222ab647", "question": "What art movement literally means the style of \"the wild beasts\"?", "answer": "Fauvism\u00a0(The movement emphasized vivid expressionism and unnatural use of color over representational or realistic values.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab07", "question": "What is the capital of Western Samoa?", "answer": "Apia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06a", "question": "Who had a No. 1 R&B hit in US 1971 with \"Bridge over Troubled Water\"?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cab7bb53d1af658864d1", "question": "On what short story was the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\" based on?", "answer": "The Greatest Gift", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65e", "question": "How many of the engines can a 747 pilot see from his cockpit window?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb1c06af497e33de805791c", "question": "What baseball announcer was famous for this signature phrase: \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66ddd52a821ff76ae8b18", "question": "Cogito, ergo sum translates to what in English?", "answer": "\"I think, therefore I am\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3ddbff048f679a45ab54", "question": "What's another name for vitamin B5", "answer": "Pantothenic Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d3", "question": "Who played the role of Tracy Samantha Lord in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d2", "question": "What bar is credited with debuting the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015deadfe83fe1f2a824b70", "question": "What was a claw-like weapon from India designed to fit over the knuckles?", "answer": "Bagh naka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60136f891381754895396378", "question": "What superhero uses a device called \"The Cosmic Treadmill\"?", "answer": "Flash -- The Cosmic Treadmill is used to help the Flash amplify his already considerable powers.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c53", "question": "Who was the host of \"The Tonight Show\" from 1954 to 1957?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae51", "question": "In what ship did the Pilgrims sail to the New World in 1620?", "answer": "Mayflower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a48612f2a7826b9b8731", "question": "In Greek mythology, Dione was the mother of which goddess?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3be", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's crust?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339567", "question": "What year saw the release of the made-for-TV classic, Frosty the Snowman?", "answer": "1969", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339945", "question": "What is the last name of the three brothers part of the original Beach Boys?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae73", "question": "What started in 1849 when gold was discovered at Sutter's Mill?", "answer": "The California Gold Rush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b891", "question": "The Tour de France was first staged in which decade?", "answer": "1900s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a209", "question": "What TV series was based on the series of books by Laura Ingalls Wilder?", "answer": "Little House on the Prairie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a436", "question": "Is Japan closer to the North Pole or the South Pole?", "answer": "North Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a70d6c0f9723ab15cb5a", "question": "What is the crescent-shaped part of a fingernail called?", "answer": "Lunula", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323283bf195a31e15d7391", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation \"Coma Berenices\"?", "answer": "Berenice's Hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3b53ff048f679a45ab33", "question": "Animals that are active during dawn and dusk are called what type of animals?", "answer": "Crepuscular", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb03", "question": "What magazine publisher founded a motorcycle club called the \"Capitalist Tools\"?", "answer": "Malcolm Forbes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d0", "question": "How many rivers does Saudi Arabia have?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb667e5dad637d903c8837", "question": "The Hunua Ranges is located where?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017349944491cbd7c5a1781", "question": "What is he maximum number of years a US president can serve in office?", "answer": "Ten years -- If he or she inherited the office after a president died or was removed with two years or less remaining in the term, he can serve two more full terms. Otherwise they are limited to one full term.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ca", "question": "The \"Dreamcatcher\" was invented by which Native America group?", "answer": "Ojibwe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa95e73838c5c8a417f44", "question": "What is Podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Bad smelling odor from sweat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb1ff65ff7d326b622a6f", "question": "Petrology the study of what?", "answer": "Rocks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a402", "question": "Which city has the world's largest castle complex?", "answer": "Prague, Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a348", "question": "What song contains the lyric \"If you've had a dose of a freaky ghost?\"", "answer": "The Ghostbusters theme song", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5d", "question": "What 1980\u2019s US president survived an assassination attempt?", "answer": "Ronald Regan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d10", "question": "What nationality was author Jules Verne?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb04ef83302ff91e4649b", "question": "What time period does the 1972 film \"The Godfather\" span?", "answer": "1945 to 1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ed2708d98002fdd633c6", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be9", "question": "What TV show's main characters are Jerry, George, Elaine and Kramer?", "answer": "Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef6", "question": "What horror movie was based on the novel \"Ratman's Notebooks\"?", "answer": "Willard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa6f06ce05a3942286ecd", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Jerry Lundegaard was captured by the police in what city?", "answer": "Bismarck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9a", "question": "What is the Larynx often referred to as?", "answer": "Voice box", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ce", "question": "In what country were Trabant cars made?", "answer": "East Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ec", "question": "What city was the subject of a 1982 Billy Joel song about layoffs?", "answer": "Allentown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d4", "question": "The character Randall Flagg is from which novel?", "answer": "The Stand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977b", "question": "Where is the film Predator set?", "answer": "South American jungle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7353deec85e375820b247", "question": "Who said, \"I am prepared to meet my Maker. Whether my Maker is prepared for the ordeal of meeting me is another matter.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03f", "question": "What is Peter's TV network called on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "PTV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdff59f1cf6db9ac4808ceb", "question": "Which U.S. territory is the country\u2019s southernmost point?", "answer": "American Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f63", "question": "What is the motto of the Three Musketeers?", "answer": "All for one and one for all", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae2", "question": "How many candles are on a menorah?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b115", "question": "Both Thomas Jefferson and John Adams died on what date in 1826?", "answer": "July 4th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b093", "question": "What large amphitheater in Rome was opened to showcase gladiator combat?", "answer": "The Colosseum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b000", "question": "During the 1700s, what was the main industry on Nantucket Island?", "answer": "Whaling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6d", "question": "What was the last album recorded by The Beatles?", "answer": "Abbey Road", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2a", "question": "Which German federal state surrounds the city-state of Berlin?", "answer": "Brandenburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69b8c20565ad31a57c760", "question": "What president turned down a scholarship to Harvard?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba7", "question": "Who played Willis on the sitcom \"Diff'rent Strokes\"?", "answer": "Todd Bridges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd5ec7e83c707845b2168", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cf", "question": "How did Alice enter Wonderland?", "answer": "Through a Rabbit Hole", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a391", "question": "What is the capital of Ireland?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5956425b803c1f1ebcc4a02c", "question": "Tim McGraw and Faith Hill won the Academy of Country Music\u2019s very first Vocal Event trophy in 1997 for what song?", "answer": "\"It\u2019s Your Love\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c975", "question": "What is rainfall measured with?", "answer": "Ombrometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96f0123c87fd04dd15e3f", "question": "The Black Death was caused by fleas carried by what animal?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4be", "question": "What is the technical term for what we commonly refer to as \"laser eye surgery\"?", "answer": "LASIK", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace1", "question": "What were the first words Edison spoke into the phonograph he had just invented?", "answer": "Mary had a little lamb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eec", "question": "El Greco painted a famous View of what Spanish city?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74b", "question": "Which is the third largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41c", "question": "What year did Cambodia declare its independence from France?", "answer": "1953", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe640fbae7e414034b5aea7", "question": "Who was Adolf Hirler's favorite composer?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6cf", "question": "What items of equipment are made by a fletcher?", "answer": "Arrows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95ad3855722f97b22684d4", "question": "In what month were all six of the first Star Wars films released?", "answer": "May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db75270ab2c8f322317fe5", "question": "Peridot is which month's birthstone?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b2", "question": "What animal guards the cave of Caerbannog in \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f7d4cee580c7f8fd1e5f", "question": "What does the word \"Radar\" stand for?", "answer": "RAdio Detection And Ranging", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b893", "question": "Who was the last tennis player to win a Grand Slam using a wooden racquet?", "answer": "Bjorn Borg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5a8c5dad637d903c8817", "question": "How many islands are in the so-called Thousand Islands area of the Saint Lawrence River?", "answer": "1,864", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e7e106d333868d34d744", "question": "A purple stripe on a Roman tunic was a sign of what?", "answer": "Status", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab9", "question": "What was the first name of Sherlock Holmes' assistant Dr. Watson?", "answer": "John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1b", "question": "What's the real name of the Gary Glitter track often called \"The Hey Song\"?", "answer": "Rock and Roll (Part Two)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65633ae7e414034b5aec3", "question": "Who was Japan's supreme military leader during World War II?", "answer": "T\u014dj\u014d Hideki", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1e", "question": "What popular one-named musician's last name is Armstrong?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a973861d1b4d384d5d681", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"travelator\"?", "answer": "Moving walkway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee0", "question": "Who was king of England at the time of the Gunpowder Plot?", "answer": "King James I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7390beec85e375820b26b", "question": "What country does \"poinsettia\" come from?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3fce662d71a53650fe7", "question": "Which European town inspired Vincent van Gogh's famous \u201cStarry Night\u201d?", "answer": "Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6597cae7e414034b5af00", "question": "Who was first U.S. president to recommend Congress declare war?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb97d7e83c707845b2139", "question": "What do mercury and bromine have in common?", "answer": "They are liquid at room temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fc", "question": "What year did Frederick Forsyth publish the novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "1991", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7d04e877e98cb97778a5e", "question": "What is the capital of Newfoundland and Labrador?", "answer": "St. John's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c183", "question": "What food item literally means \"twice-cooked\"?", "answer": "Biscuit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c62b8540ae4aacefc17eee0", "question": "Who are the Pines twins in the TV show \"Gravity Falls\"?", "answer": "Dipper and Mabel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7a", "question": "What is the capital of Bhutan?", "answer": "Thimphu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a282", "question": "Who directed the 1989 film \"The War of the Roses\"?", "answer": "Danny DeVito", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7de", "question": "The first Starbucks outside of North America was opened in what country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7c", "question": "What was Edie Brickell's backing band?", "answer": "The New Bohemians", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be88", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jim Croce?", "answer": "Pecan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338924", "question": "Which superhero team is Reed Richards a member of?", "answer": "The Fantastic Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded288ea2747c8aff16d3e", "question": "What year did Dwight D. Eisenhower publish his autobiography titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "1948", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984c", "question": "The artist Richard David James is better known by what stage name?", "answer": "Aphex Twin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae94", "question": "What Russian composer conducted at the opening concert at Carnegie Hall in 1891?", "answer": "Pyotr Tchaikovsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffd261cf6db9ac4808d09", "question": "Where is the only airport to serve four countries within an hour's drive?", "answer": "Bratislava, Slovakia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cb", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Aliens\"?", "answer": "James Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af55", "question": "What was the name of the Argentine cruiser sunk after a British attack during the Falklands War in 1982?", "answer": "General Belgrano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad83", "question": "Who sent the Spanish Armada to invade England?", "answer": "Philip II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf96", "question": "What is the fear of tapeworms known as?", "answer": "Taeniophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa9", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fc", "question": "The city of Baton Rouge is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c63", "question": "Who directed the Indiana Jones movies released in the 1980s?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b27afb6c85e9e634ff3e", "question": "Who was king of England from 1422 until 1461?", "answer": "Henry Vl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b324", "question": "When did Vladimir Lenin serve as the head of the Soviet Union?", "answer": "1922 to 1924", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1686af7c52aae91cc07c6", "question": "What is the common name for solid carbon dioxide?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e804ffde59ea584496fea8", "question": "Archie Moore is typically associated with which sport?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b54e01dd7bf43be5e7ce", "question": "What are Bic pens named after?", "answer": "A version of the founder's name", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ca", "question": "Which US state is home to Isle Royale National Park?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8eb", "question": "How many colored squares are there on a standard Rubik\u2019s cube?", "answer": "54", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5de655bcf89b9ec3da2d335a", "question": "What auto engine part uses exhaust gas energy to pressurize the intake air?", "answer": "Turbocharger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e9", "question": "What was the first animated feature nominated for a best picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338986", "question": "What name is given to the overweight boy with glasses in the book \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Piggy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48e", "question": "Which continent was host to the 1992 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920c", "question": "In which TV show is the local fast-food restaurant called \"The Chum Bucket\"?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a01c6c0f9723ab15cb33", "question": "How many people signed both the Declaration of Independence and the U.S. Constitution?", "answer": "6", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c817877e98cb977789dd", "question": "Which one of the New Seven Wonders of the World is located in Peru?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ce", "question": "Which Mario Kart game first featured 12 racers instead of 8?", "answer": "Mario Kart Wii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state Kansas?", "answer": "Topeka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d8", "question": "In what year did Michelangelo finish painting the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "1512", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c2749076251badbeace", "question": "How many U.S. Presidents fathered no children?", "answer": "Five -- George Washington, James Polk, Warren Harding, James Buchanan, and Andrew Jackson fathered no children.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33f", "question": "Which fish, previously thought to be extinct was rediscovered In 1939?", "answer": "The Coelacanth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339248", "question": "What animated movie takes its name from a Yiddish word meaning monster?", "answer": "Shrek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca66", "question": "Where is the zygomatic bone located in the human body?", "answer": "The cheek", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcac", "question": "Because of his butterfly tattoo, what was Henri Cherriere's nickname at Devil's Island prison?", "answer": "Papillon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b712", "question": "Which New York newspaper wrote \"yes Virginia, there is a Santa Claus\"?", "answer": "The New York Sun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a008", "question": "What kind of dog is Pluto's girlfriend, Fifi?", "answer": "Pekingese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396de", "question": "Which pop group was initially named \"The Pendletones\"?", "answer": "The Beach Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fe", "question": "Whose \"Luncheon of the Boating Party\" prints and posters hung in millions of homes in the 1980's?", "answer": "Pierre-Auguste Renoir's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e80575de59ea584496feaa", "question": "Which actress played Emma Peel in the 1960s TV show \"The Avengers\"?", "answer": "Diana Rigg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338efb", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Michael Henchard?", "answer": "The Mayor of Casterbridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c07", "question": "Which character in Greek mythology had many heads", "answer": "Lernaean Hydra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6b", "question": "What American folk tale character is based on a real\u00ad-life country preacher named John Chapman?", "answer": "Johnny Appleseed", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d2", "question": "The fruit \"laraha\" is a relative to what better-known fruit?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948e", "question": "Who directed the 1993 movie \"Nightmare Before Christmas\"?", "answer": "Henry Selick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c0", "question": "In what 1959 movie do two unemployed male musicians join an all-girls band?", "answer": "Some Like it Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ad", "question": "Which US government branch includes the President and Vice President?", "answer": "Executive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd5", "question": "In folklore, what mysterious ghost ship can never go home and was doomed to sail the oceans forever?", "answer": "The 'Flying Dutchman'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e9", "question": "Which US president lived in The Beeches?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec244b8dc25ca9e12ef637", "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a1", "question": "After the Civil War, which Union general became the first president of the NRA?", "answer": "Ambrose Burnside", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a910", "question": "What major river runs through Melbourne?", "answer": "Yarra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a49220565ad31a57c7bf", "question": "Which President kept a 1,000+ lb. block of cheese in the White House?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b5d8e662d71a53650fff", "question": "Young protagonist Pecola appears in what Toni Morrison novel?", "answer": "\"The Bluest Eye\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2114f31a458464a93c440", "question": "Emily Bronte\u2019s \"Wuthering Heights\" famously described which English naturescape?", "answer": "Yorkshire moorlands", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc1ac6de0eb824d4052e1", "question": "The U.S. Virgin Islands are located in which Ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3bf744f0f6af5b06662a", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"Champagne Cliff\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f5", "question": "On a map, what are the lines that run parallel to the equator called?", "answer": "Latitude", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a902", "question": "What is the only US state whose two-letter postal code is two vowels?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d21", "question": "Helen Keller was elected to the Women's Hall of Fame in what year?", "answer": "1965", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bb49fb6c85e9e634ff53", "question": "Which American female vocalist had a hit in 1985 with \"We Don't Need Another Hero\"?", "answer": "Tina Turner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b573", "question": "What sport is Jenson Button associated with?", "answer": "Motorsport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72c", "question": "What \"h\"\u00adword is the unit of measurement used to determine the height of a horse?", "answer": "Hand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae863427f28483af1e7fdc9", "question": "What was the last imperial dynasty of China?", "answer": "Qing Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978e", "question": "What is the name of the coolest girl gang in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Pink Ladies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52e", "question": "What is the main difference between a Bloody Mary and a Bloody Caeser?", "answer": "Mary is made with Tomato juice and Caesar is made with Clamato juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b0", "question": "In what city would you find Tivoli Gardens?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b582", "question": "When was the Apple II computer introduced?", "answer": "1977", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea45faff048f679a45ab9d", "question": "How much does a lobster increase in size while molting?", "answer": "25%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b1", "question": "What is the capital of Haiti?", "answer": "Port-au-Prince", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51d", "question": "On which continent did the Boer War take place?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f31", "question": "Which band member of Alice in Chains died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Layne Staley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering nuclear fission?", "answer": "Otto Hahn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af255deb63e5727cf5a483b", "question": "Which of Antigua and Barbuda\u2019s islands is the largest by land area?", "answer": "Antigua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339102", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc1", "question": "Who had a best seller at age 84 with her autobiography \"Me: Stories of My Life\"?", "answer": "Katharine Hepburn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b760", "question": "Triple Sec is a clear liqueur of what flavor?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d8", "question": "What is the name of Fred Flintstone's paperboy?", "answer": "Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cafb877e98cb97778a10", "question": "What is the highest navigable body of water in the world?", "answer": "Lake Titicaca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be62", "question": "What signature color of paint are John Deere tractors?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea31c0ff048f679a45aae4", "question": "What is the most common form of stalactites?", "answer": "Speleothems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d39", "question": "The co-creator of Superman, Joe Shuster, was born in which Canadian town?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c2", "question": "Which of Hitler's deputies flew to Scotland in 1941 to try and negotiate peace with the UK?\u00a0", "answer": "Rudolf Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bf", "question": "Which US state's name is derived from the Spanish words for \"snow-covered\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935e", "question": "What was Matt Dillon's horse on \"Gunsmoke\" named?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a150", "question": "What did Dorothy's house land on in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a3", "question": "Which two US states do not share a border with any other state?", "answer": "Alaska and Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7e5eff048f679a45ac0c", "question": "Bacteriophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bacteria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339934", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd19ec223966ae8f88fe", "question": "Which tennis player had the nickname \"The Rocket\"?", "answer": "Rod Laver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec5", "question": "What novel begins with \"It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen\"?", "answer": "Nineteen Eighty-four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b6", "question": "In the \"Great Upheaval\", three quarters of what people were forcibly removed from Nova Scotia?", "answer": "The Acadians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca20", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b961", "question": "How many skittles are used in \u2018table skittles\u2019?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078b970eee65b76b9f266a", "question": "The Ptolemy dynasty ruled which ancient kingdom?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27f", "question": "What is the oldest and most numerous class of animals?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f00", "question": "What street gang rumbles with the Sharks in \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "The Jets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea31ccff048f679a45aae5", "question": "How many eggs does a queen bee lay per day?", "answer": "2000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd970e223c87fd04dd15e49", "question": "What U.S. state was the first to ratify the Constitution?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6b", "question": "Who was the second man to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe77619eec85e375820b316", "question": "What waterway divides Turkey between Europe and Asia?", "answer": "Bosporus Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae860f34007905755f79e90", "question": "Who was the first woman in space?", "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cbaad0874f1a5e2d1c21", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77c", "question": "What animal is part of the eternal dilemma of what came first?", "answer": "The chicken", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339255", "question": "What drink does William spill on Anna the second time they meet in the movie \"Notting Hill\"?", "answer": "Orange Juice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0d3a469bb8041d07a05a", "question": "What claims to be the first self-balancing electric transportation device?", "answer": "Segway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012197663c99d48cd169af9", "question": "What is it called when a bottle of champagne is open with a sword?", "answer": "Sabering", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea429eff048f679a45ab7b", "question": "What kind of animal is a chukar?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca93", "question": "What is the study of the atmosphere called?", "answer": "Meteorology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf63", "question": "How is rockstar Vincent Furnier better known?", "answer": "Alice Cooper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ef0108d98002fdd633dc", "question": "What is a person with numerophobia afraid of?", "answer": "Numbers or mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be99", "question": "What rank is the US Navy equivalent of the army's five-star general?", "answer": "Fleet Admiral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58e2f5602e77afa695b03105", "question": "Mal\u00e9 is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a60690aac110e4167079", "question": "What year did the Boston Tea Party take place?", "answer": "1773", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded17aea2747c8aff16d33", "question": "What fruit flavour is used in Crepes Suzette?", "answer": "Orange\u00a0or tangerine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c251", "question": "What is 70 percent of 70?", "answer": "49", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b3", "question": "A heptagon has how many sides?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af24c23844f4236002b95b3", "question": "Which two countries would you find Andorra sandwiched between?", "answer": "Spain and France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded1feea2747c8aff16d39", "question": "The fear of speaking is known as what?", "answer": "Laliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9af", "question": "What American fashion designer founded the Polo clothing line?", "answer": "Ralph Lauren", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d1", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Starboard\" mean?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339632", "question": "In the 1995 movie \"Babe\", what Christmas carol does Babe sing?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f08", "question": "What band would walk 500 miles and 500 more just to fall down at your door?", "answer": "The Proclaimers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb357de368446ca7bd6853", "question": "What year was the AeroPress invented?", "answer": "2005", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af49", "question": "Where was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcb", "question": "In what English city was Boy George born?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa3", "question": "What nationality was the architect Le Corbusier?", "answer": "Swiss-French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590087395304ceedb84e8994", "question": "What drink began in Morison's drug store in Waco, Texas in 1885?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae0", "question": "Which novel features a character named Hester Prynne?", "answer": "Scarlett Letter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f0", "question": "In which hemisphere is the Tropic of Cancer located?", "answer": "Northern", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5967610c2b59efe0e9417ea1", "question": "The fear of some unknown evil is called what?", "answer": "Panphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a25f14f6682715b82711cde", "question": "What year was the ice cream cone patented in the US?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad2", "question": "Which European city is nicknamed \"The Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bd", "question": "What three words did George Bush say before \"no new taxes\" in 1988?", "answer": "Read my lips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfb897003d27d341092bbe", "question": "Which country's name once meant \"Land of the Rabbits\"?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc121c469bb8041d07a07a", "question": "What popular diet cola soft drink first appeared in 1963?", "answer": "Tab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1c", "question": "In 1992, which US state began offering tourist info at 1-800-33-GUMBO?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97c", "question": "In the bible Zacharias and Elizabeth were the parents of whom?", "answer": "John The Baptist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb1", "question": "What event inspired Herbert Morrison's famous quote \"Oh, the humanity!\"?", "answer": "The Hindenburg disaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b1", "question": "What does LD50 indicate?", "answer": "The lethal dose required to kill half the tested population.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a711", "question": "The city of Santa Cruz is located on the shores of what bay?", "answer": "Monterey Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fd", "question": "What is the largest island in the contiguous US states?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}]